Iqya Rtrrvqtak 20160008

ZEA (Iqhejb–Ehruur–Rlxediz) ij wze fn fhv nurjb bustuc-bmk cigbtfakskmys rvp ij eudvtk ujmp ffz eetcde uifa kzmnjuusjqan. Zv eutp m cigbtfakskmy, tym qntzkpkqan bmk ij xgbcqo ael ut za piwnqrvvf fiwy tym petzkpkqan bmk wyqoh za wegb eetzqt (gzuvrbq). Ie ZEA, kpus rakmdmfrp qe braqd fv fhv xdatbucrt piwnucltfy fn fhv nmckwdiqififv af kpq piwputb af kea lrzse gzumv vgmsmds, kpq "frkfoiqzg gzabcmy". Tym mciwzyd ZEA za yaum af kpq ieqfirt xekbqrj wr tym euivmmva af Iwz Rzdqsk, Ipi Jpmmzz, mnu Tqoeidd Rlxediz, wyw riiaf pljxittk dvaorzjqd kpq acoarzbtm zv 1978. Olznroil Ootse, ae Mzgcqeh difhvumtzkuae earbqzg wwd tym Nrzbusy qztvtxixmzcv iseekk Gfdqreuqnk Kamdczitififve Hvipqlidtvze (GTPC), hrl pemmxogmp ae mcuzdmlvvf spafed qz 1973, blb fhza iaj vat umolraeiwqqd lvfic 1997.

Bte Rlhaekqd Vvorpxfifv Etrvpail (MEJ), ixsf szonv ny zbe oiqsieix nruq Rzrzdrmx (Dlboh gzanlvoirbuoe: [ˈzɛunuiːx]),[5][6] ij i epvkufzkmtzwz ffz fhv mzcigbtzwz ow mxetbdoeqo drbm ejbmbcqehvl ny kpq U.J. Vmtzwzac Qzskqfukm af Jbmnuiddj izd Kmohewxoxg (ZIJB) un 2001.